Finding Aid for the Charles S. Mitchell Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Charles S. Mitchell Collection
June, 1966
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0293
2.52 linear feet
- Playbills - Programs - 1876-1963 ca. 450 items - (45 N.D.)
- Librettos - 6 items
- Miscellaneous pamphlets - 20 items
- Photographs of actors, actresses and musicians
- Newspaper clippings
- Correspondence, incoming, Cheatham, Frances B. (no date) - 1 letter Milne, A. C. - 1929, July 24 - 1 letter Robinson, Francis - 1949, Sept. 24 - 1 letter “Buddy” - no date - 1 letter No signature - no date 4 letters - 1 card
- The Old Vic Company, 1914-1963
  - Issued to commemorate the final performance saturday, 15th June, 1963
- The Old Vic Company, 1914-1963 is located with the English Dept.’s materials, Location of everything else: M/2/15
- includes correspondence and playbills from, 1866-1921 (Box 1)
- includes correspondence and playbills from, 1922-1934 (Box 2)
- includes correspondence and playbills from, 1936-1947 (Box 3)
- includes correspondence and playbills from 1948-1952; playbills from 1952-1963 donated by Mitchell’s friend Herschel Gower, faculty member of the Vanderbilt English Department; and programs with no date. (Box 4)
- includes newspaper clippings, librettos, pamphlets, playbills, miscellaneous. Some of the playbills in Box 5 were also donated by Herschel Gower. Theatre Vendome programs (ca. 1913-1916), which were printed on newsprint paper and thus are extremely fragile, are included in this Box. (Box 5)
- includes photographs of theatrical performers. (Box 6)
- Correspondence--Incoming
  - Cheatham, Frances B, n.d., 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Milne, A. C, July 24, 1929, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Robinson, Francis, September 24, 1949, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - “Buddy,”, n.d., 1 letter (Box 1)
  - No signature, n.d., 4 letters, 1 card (Box 1)
- Playbills--Programs (1866)
  - (Box 1)
    Belphegor the Mountebank stars Chas. Dillion Cherry Street Theatre, N
    Bohemian Girl! By M. W. Balfe and farce Dobson Bamboozled! Holman Opera Troupe, N
    Hanlon Brothers! (gymnasts) and Prof. Sylvester! and Mrs. W. Tanner! N
    Ingomar the Barbarian stars Jean Hosmer and farce Rough Diamond! N
    La Tour de Nesle! or The Chamber of Death and burletta Anthony & Cleopatra Cherry Street Theatre, N
    Lucretia Borgia! or The Poisoner! stars Jean Hosmer and drama Jack Sheppard: the House-Breaker Cherry Street Theatre, N
    Mazeppa! or, The Young King of Tartary adapted from Lord Byron’s drama stars Adah Issacs Menken includes Nashville Tennesean clipping on Menken (July 28, 1948) N
- (1867)
  - (Box 1)
    Lady of Lyons or Love and Pride stars Charlotte Thompson and The Merry Cobbler Adelphi Theatre, N
    Little Treasure stars Charlotte Thompson and Day After the Wedding Adelphi Theatre, N
    The Streets of New York Adelphi Theatre, N
- (1868-69)
  - (Box 1)
    Grand Vocal Concert, Second Baptist on Tuesday, September 29, 1868 Cherry Street, N
    Bianca the Italian Wife stars Jean Hosmer and Fazio! or The Italian Wife’s Revenge by Reverend Henry Hart Milmore and The Toodles! New Nashville Theatre, N
    Elizabeth Queen of England stas Mrs. F. W. Lander New Nashville Theatre, N
    Grand Concert Benefit of West Nashville M. E. Church, South on Friday, October 29, 1869 N
    Grand Medley Concert at Masonic Hall on December 16, 17, 1869 N
    Grand Sunday School Concert at Masonic Hall on Monday, July 19, 1869 N
    Grand Vocal and Instrumental Concert at Masonic Hall on Friday, June 18, 1869 N
    School for Scandal stars Mrs. F. W. Lander New Nashville Theatre, N
- (1870-74)
  - (Box 1)
    Grand Concert for the Benefit of the Church of the Advent at Masonic Hall on Tuesday, November 1, 1970 N
    Mary Stuart, Schiller’s Historical Play, stars Janauschek, 1873 Masonic Hall, N
    Everybody’s Friend! stars John E. Owens, 1874 and Solon Shingle Opera House, N
    Happy Man! (Irish oriental farce) stars J. Holmes Grover and Handy Andy! N
    The Heir-at-Law! (grand English comedy) stars John E. Owens, 1874 and 40 Winks! Opera House, N
    Peak Family Bell Ringers!
    Tosso (violinist), Emily Young (vocalist), McCann (ventriloquist) and Melzell1 s French Troupe of Fantoccini unidentifiable music program
- (1876-96)
  - (Box 1)
    Edmund Kean by Alex. Dumas stars Ernesto Rossi, 1882 and a scene from King Lear Chestnut Street Opera House, P
    A Night Off or A Page from Balzac by Augustin Daly, 1885 and Epilogue in Verse by Edgar Fawcett Daly’s Theatre, NY
    Nancy and Company by Augustin Daly, 1886 Daly’s Theatre, NY
    Magda by H. Sudermann, English argument by E. Beall Ginty, 1896 The Bernhardt edition
    Pique! Daly’s Fifth Avenue Theatre, NY
- (1897-99)
  - (Box 1)
    Irish-American Centennial Association of Tennessee Booklet, September 21, 1897
    A Contented Woman, 1898 New Masonic Theatre, N
    The Highwayman Theatre Vendome, N
    The Little Minister by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams Hollis Street Theatre B
- (1900)
  - (Box 1)
    The Burgomaster, 50th performance theatre souvenir Dearborn Thatre
- (1901)
  - (Box 1)
    Beaucaire (2) a comedy by Booth Tarkington and Evelyn G. Sutherland, stars Richard Mansfield Colonial Theatre, B
    Florodora, an English musical comedy, book by Owen Hall and music by Leslie Stuart The New York Theatre, NY
    Hoity Toity, a Giddy Little Skit on Things Dramatic and Otherwise, lyrics by Edgar Smith and music by John Stromberg Webster & Fields Music Hall, NY
    If I Were King by Justin H. McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern Garden Theatre, NY
    L’Aiglon by Edmond Rostand, adapted into English by Louis N. Parker, a pictorial souvenir R. H. Russell Publisher, NY
    Miranda of the Balcony by Anne C. Flexner stars Mrs. Fiske Manhattan Theatre, NY
    Mrs. Dane’s Defence by Henry Arthur Jones Hollis Street Theatre, B
    Sky Farm, a simple story of the Berkshire Hills, by Edward E. Kidder Boston Museum, B
    Otis Skinner Presenting George H. Boker’s Tragedy Francesca Da Rimini (Book)
- (1902)
  - (Box 1)
    Grand Opera House Program: week of May 5, 1902
    The Merchant May 5
    The First Anniversary May 7
    The Camp Scene from Virginius
    The Death Shot
    One Touch of Nature May 9
    Comedy and Tragedy by W. S. Gilbert
    The Balcony Scene from Romeo and Juliet
    N
- (1903)
  - (Box 1)
    The Marble Heart by Charles Selbey Grand Opera House, N
    The Merchant of Venice by William Shakespeare Grand Opera House, N
- (1904)
  - (Box 1)
    The Darling of the Gods stars Blanche Bates David’s Belasco’s Exposition Production
- (1905)
  - (Box 1)
    As Ye Sow, a drama founded on life and incidents on Cape Cod, by Rev. John M. Snyder Majestic Theatre, B
    Camille, La Dame aux Camelias, by Alexandre Dumas The Sarah Bernhardt edition
    Camille Ryman Auditorium, N
    Man and Superman by Bernard Shaw Hudson Theatre, NY
    The Music Master by Charles Klein stars David Warfield Bijou Theatre, NY
    Oliver Twist by Charles Dickens Proctor’s Fifth Avenue Theatre NY
    Zaza stars Mrs. Leslie Carter Belasco Theatre, NY
    Zira by J. Hartley Manners and Henry Mille stars Margaret Anglin Princess Theatre, NY
- (1906)
  - (Box 1)
    A Parisian Romance by Octave Feuillet Colonial Theatre, B
- (1907)
  - (Box 1)
    Divorcons by Victorien Sardou, adapted from the French by Margaret Mayo, stars Grace George Hollis Street, B
    The Great Divide by William Vaughn Moody stars Margaret Anglin and Henry Miller Daly’s Theatre, NY
    The Master Builder by Henrik Ibsen Bijou Theatre, NY
- (1908)
  - (Box 1)
    The Melting Pot by Israel Zangwill stars Mr. Whiteside Chicago Opera House C
- (1909)
  - (Box 1)
    Anna Lundberg Concert on September 12, 1909 Orchestra Hall, C
    The Climax by Edward Locke Weber’s Theatre, NY
    The Easiest Way by Eugene Walter stars Frances Starr Belasco’s Theatre, NY
    The Man from Home by Booth Tarkington and Harry Leon Wilson stars Mr. William Hodge Astor Theatre, NY
    The Messiah by Handel Apollo Musical Club, C
    The Passing of the Third Floor Back by Jerome K. Jerome Maxine Elliott’s Theatre, NY
    What Every Woman Knows by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams Grand Opera House, C
- (1910)
  - (Box 1)
    Herod by Stephen Phillips stars William Faversham Garrick Theatre
    La Samaritaine by M•. Edmond Rostand stars Sarah Bernhardt and Company The Studebaker, C
    Madame X by Alexandre Bisson as presented by by Sarah Bernhardt (argument of the play)
    Mr. Mantell and his Company in a Repertoire of Shakespearean and Other Classical Plays for the week of November 21, 1910
    King Lear
    Louis XI
    Romeo and Juliet
    Macbeth
    The Merchant of Venice
    Richard III
    Lyric Theatre, C
    Ragged Robin· stars Chauncey Olcott McVicker’s Theatre, C
    Ruth by Georg Schumann Apollo Musical Club, C
- (1911)
  - (Box 1)
    The Concert by Herman Bahr Belasco Theatre, NY
    Disraeli by Louis N. Parker Wallack’s, NY
    The Great Name by James Clarence Harvey Thirty-ninth Street Theatre, NY
    Return of Peter Grimm by David Belasco Belasco Theatre, NY
    Shakespeare
    The Taming of the Shrew
    Hamlet
    Lyric, C
    Thais (in French) Lyric Romance by Jules Massenet Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera C
    The Thief adapted into English by Haddon Chambers Daily’s Theatre, NY
    Bunty Pulls the Strings, A Scottish Comedy, by Graham Moffat William Collier’s Comedy Theatre NY NY
- (1912)
  - (Box 1)
    Chantecler by Edmond Rostand Illinois Theatre, C
- (1913)
  - (Box 1)
    Romance by Edward Sheldon The Princess Theatre, C
    The Wall Street Girl, book by Margaret Maho and Egar Selwyn and music by Karl Hoschna, stars Will Rogers Theatre Vendome, N
- (1914)
  - (Box 1)
    Caesar and Cleopatra by George Bernard Shaw Blackstone Theatre, C
    If I Were King by Justin Huntley McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern
    Our American Cousin by Tom Taylor stars E. H. Sothern
    Hamlet by William Shakespeare stars E. H. Sothern
    Charlemagne by Justin Huntley McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern
    Garrick Theatre, C
- (1915)
  - (Box 1)
    Androcles and the Lion by George Bernard Shaw Powers’ Theatre, C
- (1915)
  - (Box 1)
    The Man Who Married a Dumb Wife by Anatole France Powers’ Theatre, C
    Anna Pavlowa and Her Ballet Russe April 2, 1915 Auditorium Theatre, C
    Song Recital by John McCormack Benefit Performance for Italian Red Cross and Invalid Pensioners Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera C
- (1916)
  - (Box 1)
    Common Clay by Cleves Kinkead Olympic Theatre, C
    Hamlet (Farewell of Forbes-Robertson to the the American Stage on April 24, 25, 26, 1916, Shakespeare Tercentenary) at Harvard Cambridge, Massachusetts
    His Majesty Bunker Bean by Lee Wilson Dodd Cort Theatre, C
    The Little Minister by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams Blackstone Theatre, C
    The Two Virtues by Alfred Sutro Blackstone Theatre, C
- (1918)
  - (Box 1)
    Lilac-Time by Jane Cowl and Jane Murfin George M. Cohan Grand Opera House C
- (1919)
  - (Box 1)
    Aida (in Italian) by Giuseppe Verdi Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera C
    The Acquittal by Rita Weiman George M. Cohan Grand Opera House C
    Déclassée by Zoe Akins stars Ethel Barrymore Empire Theatre, NY
    First Annual Testimonial Performance in the Interest of the Actors’ Fidelity League Sunday, October 12, 1919 Century Theatre, NY
    The Gold Diggers by Avery Hopwood Lyceum Theatre, NY
    Happiness by J. Hartley Manners Blackstone Theatre, C
    Jacques Duvall (adapted) by George S. Kaufman Blackstone Theatre, C
    The Jest (adapted from the Italian of Sem Benelli’s La Cena delle Beffe) stars Johri and Lionel Barrymore settings by Robert Edmund Jones Plymouth Theatre, NY
- (1919)
  - (Box 1)
    Lightin’ by Winchell Smith and Frank Bacon Gaiety Theatre, NY
    The Masquerader by John Hunter Booth Studebaker Theatre, C
    Tillie by Helen Martin and Frank Howe, Jr. Blackstone Theatre, C
- (1920)
  - (Box 1)
    The Barber of Seville (in Italian) by Rossini Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera C
- (1921)
  - (Box 1)
    The Woman of Bronze by Paul Kester Princess Theatre, C
- (1922)
  - (Box 2)
    The Circle by W. Somerset Maugham Selwyn Theatre, C
    Sir Harry Lauder Shubert Great Northern, C
    Nice People by Rachel Crothers Cort Theatre, C
    The Silver Fox by Cosmo Hamilton La Salle Theatre, C
    La Traviata by Verdi Chicago Civic Opera, C
- (1923)
  - (Box 2)
    The School for Scandal by Richard Sheridan Lyceum Theatre, NY
    So This is London by Arthur Goodrich George M. Cohan’s Opera House NY
    Windows (2) by John Galsworthy Garrick Theatre, NY
- (1924)
  - (Box 2)
    Wappin’ Wharf, a frightful comedy of pirates, by Charles S. Brooks Little Theatre of Birmingham, Alabama
- (1925)
  - (Box 2)
    Charlot’s Revue Selwyn Theatre, NY
    The Green Rat by Michael Arlen Selwyn Theatre, NY
    Hamlet with Walter Hampden and Ethel Barrymore Hampden’s, NY
    Is Zat So? by James Gleason and Richard Taber Chanin’s Forty-sixth Street Theatre, NY
    Rose-Marie by Otto Harbach and Oscar Hammerstein Imperial Theatre, NY
    The Second Mrs. Tanqueray by Sir Arthur Wing Pinero Blackstone Theatre, C
    The Show-off, a transcript of life, by George Kelly New Park Theatre, B
    Stolen Fruit by Dario Niccodemi Eltinge Theatre, NY
    They Knew What They Wanted by Sidney Howard Ktaw Theatre, NY
    The Vortex by Noel Coward Henry Miller’s Theatre, NY
- (1926)
  - (Box 2)
    Black Velvet by Willard Robertson Playhouse Theatre, C
    The Master Builder by Henrik Ibsen Shubert Princess Theatre, C
    The Miracle by Maz Reinhardt Shubert Auditorium Theatre, C
    Q by Stephen Leacock and Basil MacDonald Hastings Player’s Playhouse of Ypsilanti
    The School for Scandal by Richard Sheridan Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Star Sapphire by Robert Housum Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Vanishing Princess by John Golden Player’s Playhouse of Ypsilanti
    What Every Woman Knows by J. M. Barrie Four Cohans Theatre, NY
    The Yellow Triangle by George Sutton, Jr. Player’s Playhouse of Ypsilanti NY
    Drama Calender for February 22, 1926 NY
- (1927)
  - (Box 2)
    Butterfly Hearts by Marion H. Mimms Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Host by Ferenc Molnar Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Mrs. Bumpstead-Leigh by Harry James Smith Hillsboro Theatre, N
    White Elephants by Kenyon Nicholson Hillsboro Theatre, N
- (1928)
  - (Box 2)
    The Bachelor Father by Edward Childs Carpenter Hollis Street Theatre, B
    The Butter and Egg Man by George Kaufmann and Marc Connelly Little Theatre Guild, N
    The Constant Wife by W. Somerset Maugham Sam H. Harris Theatre, C
    Coquette by George Abbot and Ann Preston Bridgers stars Helen Hayes Shubert-Wilbur Theatre, B
    The Civic Repertory Theatre Program for the weeks of October 8 and 15
    The Cradle Song by Gregorio and Maria M. Sierra
    Hedda Gabler by Henrik Ibsen (rev. trans.) by Julie Le Gallienne and Paul Leyssac
    La Locandiera by Carlo Goldoni (trans. and adapted) by Helen Lohmann
    L’Invitation Au Voyage by Jean-Jacques Bernard (trans.) by Ernest Boyd
    The Would-Be Gentleman by Moliere (adapted) by F. Anstey
    Civic Repertory Theatre, NY
- (1928)
  - (Box 2)
    Exceeding Small by Caroline Francke The Comedy Theatre, NY
    Goin’ Home by Ransom Rideout Theatre Masque, NY
    Machinal by Sophie Treadwell The Plymouth Theatre, NY
    The Red Robe by Stanley Weyman Sam S. Shubert Theatre, B
    S. S. Incorporated by Verne Jay and Frances Jewett Repertory Theatre of Boston, B
    Strange Interlude by Eugene O’Neil The Golden Theatre, NY
    Civic Repertory Theatre Schedule of Plays for the weeks of October 22-November 12 Civic Repertory Theatre, NY
- (1929)
  - (Box 2)
    It’s a Wise Child by Laurence Johnson Belasco Theatre, NY
    Strictly Dishonorable by Preston Sturges Avon Theatre, NY
- (1930)
  - (Box 2)
    The Cradle Song by G. and Maria Martinez Sierra Nashville Little Theatre, N
    Her Husband’s Wife by A. E. Thomas Nashville Little Theatre, N
    The Royal Family by Edna Ferber and George Kaufman Nashville Little Theatre, N
    The Sea Gull by Anton Tcheckov Nashville Little Theatre, N
- (1931)
  - (Box 2)
    The Barretta of Wimpole Street by R. Besier Empire Theatre, NY
    Broadway by George Abbot and Phillip Dunning Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Dancing Mothers by Edwin Goulding and Edgar Selwyn Hillsboro Theatre, N
    A Doll’s House by Henrik Ibsen Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Fourth Wall by A. A. Milne Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Front Page by Ben Hecht and C.. MacArthur Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Grand Hotel by Vicki Baum National Theatre, NY
    The Guardsman by Ferene Molnar Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Mrs. Moonlight by Benn W. Levy Little Theatre, NY
    A Noble Outcast by John Frazer Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Petticoat Influence by Neil Grant Lyceum Theatre, NY
    Private Lives by Noel Coward Times Square Theatre, NY
    The Queen’s Husband by Robert Emmet Sherwood Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Three’s A Company by Howard Dietz Selwyn Theatre, NY
    The Vinegar Tree by Paul Osborn Playhouse Theatre, NY
- (1932)
  - (Box 2)
    The Boor by Anton Tchekov Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Cynara by Philip Merivale Sam S. Shubert Theatre, NY
    Diplomacy by Victorien Sardou Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Ghosts by Henrik Ibsen Hillsboro Theatre, N
    Ladies of the Jury by Fred Ballard Hillsboro Tneatre, N
    The Lost Sheep by Andrew Nelson Lytle Hillsboro Theatre, N
    The Valiant by Holworthy Hall and Robert Middlemass Hillsboro Theatre, N
- (1933)
  - (Box 2)
    Alien Corn by Sidney Howard Harris Theatre, C
- (1934)
  - (Box 2)
    Alice Sit-by-the-Fire by Sir James Barrie Nashville Experimental Theatre, N
    Ah, Wilderness! by Eugene O’Neil with George M. Cohan Plymouth Theatre, B
    Between Two Worlds by Elmer Rice Belasco Theatre, NY
    Dodsworth by Sinclair Lewis Sam S. Shubert Theatre, NY
    The Distaff Side by John Van Druten The Booth Theatre, NY
    Judgment Day by Elmer Rice Fulton Theatre, NY
    Merrily We Roll Along by George S. Kaufman and Moss Hart The Music Box, NY
    The Mikado by W. S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan Martin Beck Theatre, NY
    Once in a Lifetime by George Kaufman and Moss Nashville Experimental Theatre, N
    Personal Appearance by Lawrence Riley Henry Miller’s Theatre, NY
    A Sleeping Clergyman by James Bridie Guild Theatre, NY
    Stevedore by Paul Peters and George Sklar Civic Repertory Theatre, NY
    Tobacco Road by Jack Kirkland (based on a novel by Erskine Caldwell) Forrest Theatre, NY
    Tristan and Isolde by Richard Wagner Chicago Grand Opera, C
- (1936)
  - (Box 3)
    Boy Meets Girl by Bella and Samuel Spewack Cort Theatre, NY
    Bury the Dead by Irwin Shaw preceded by Prelude (Actors’ Repertory Company) Ethel Barrymore Theatre, NY
    Children’s Hour by Lillian Hellman Maxine Elliott’s Theatre, NY
    Dead End by Sidney Kingsley Belasco Theatre, NY
    Idiot’s Delight by Robert Sherwood Sam. S. Shubert Theatre, NY
    Victoria Regina by Laurence Housman Broadhurst Theatre, NY
- (1938)
  - (Box 3)
    Federal Theatre Presents Summer 1938 Program
- (1942)
  - (Box 3)
    Blithe Spirit by Noel Coward Booth Theatre, NY
    Eve of St. Mark by Maxwell Anderson Cort Theatre, NY
    The Gondoliers by W. S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan Nashville Community Playhouse
    Hello Out There by William Saroyan Magic by G. K. Chesterton Belasco Theatre, NY
    Janie by Antoinette Perry Henry Miller’s Theatre, NY
    Petticoat Forever by Mark Reed Nashville Community Theatre
    Sons O’ Fun by Ole Olsen and Chic Johnson Winter Garden Theatre, NY
    Strip for Action by Howard Lindsay and Russell Crouse National Theatre, NY
    Uncle Harry by Thomas Job Hudson Theatre, NY
- (1943)
  - (Box 3)
    Claudia by Rose Franken Nashville Community Playhouse
    The Doughgirls by Joseph Fields Lyceum Theatre, NY
    Harriet by Florence Ryerson and Colin Clements Henry Miller’s Theatre, NY
    Kiss and Tell by F. Hugh Herbert Biltmore Theatre, NY
    The Merry Widow Majestic Theatre, NY
    Lady in the Dark by Moss Hart Civic Opera House, C
    The Philadelphia Story by Philip Barry Nashville Community Playhouse
    Porgy and Bess by George Gershwin and Du Bose Heyard Forty-fourth Street Theatre, NY
    Tomorrow the World by James Gow and Arnaud d’Usseau Ethel Barrymore Theatre, NY
- (1944)
  - (Box 3)
    Arsenic and Old Lace by Joseph Kesselring Nashville Community Playhouse
    Buddies by George V. Hobart Produced by Smyrna Army and Field Dramatic Club
    Nashville Community Playhouse
    Chicken Every Sunday by Julius J. and Philip G. Epstein Plymouth Theatre, NY
    Decision by Edward Chodorov Ambassador Theatre, NY
    Jacobonsky and the Colonel (original play) by Franz Werfel (American play) by S. N. Behrman Martin Beck Theatre, NY
    Letters to Lucerne by Fritz Rotter and Allen Vincent Nashville Community Playhouse
    The New Moon: An Operetta in Three Acts by Sigmund Romberg, Oscar Hammerstein 2nd, Frank Mandel, and Laurence Schwab New York City Center of Music and Drama
    Othello by William Shakespeare starring Paul Robeson Sam S. Shubert Theatre, NY
    The Searching Wind by Lillian Hellman Fulton Theatre, NY
    Spring Again by Isabel Leighton and Bertram Bloch Nashville Community Playhouse
    3 Is a Family by Phoebe and Henry Ephron Belasco, NY
    The Voice of the Turtle by John Van Druten Moresco Theatre, NY
- (1945)
  - (Box 3)
    A Bell for Adano by Paul Osborn (based on John Hersey’s novel) Cort Theatre, NY
    The Barretts of Wimpole Street by Rudolf Besier Ethel Barrymore Theatre, NY
    Dark of the Moon by Howard Richardson and William Berney Forty-Sixth Street Theatre, NY
    Dinner at Eight by Edna Ferber and George S. Kaufman Nashville Community Playhouse
    Foolish Notion by Philip Barry (starring Tallulah Bankhead) Martin Beck Theatre, NY
    Foxhole in the Parlor by Elsa Shelley The Booth Theatre, NY
    Harvey by Mary Chase Forty-Eighth Street Theatre, NY
    The Hasty Heart by John Patrick Hudson Theatre, NY
    *Second Decade of the Playhouse, a Publication of the Nashville Community Playhouse, Oct. 8, 1945 N
    Hollywood Pinafore (Or the Lad Who Loved a Salary) (book & lyrics revised by George S. Kaufman Alvin Theatre, NY
    I Remeber Mama by John Van Druten (music by Richard Rogers and Oscar Hammerstein, 2nd) The Music Box, NY
    Oklahoma! (based on the play “Green Grow the Lilacs” by Lynn Riggs) (music by Richard Rogers and Oscar Hammerstein, 2nd) St. James Theatre, NY
    The Old Ladies by Rodney Ackland (adapted from a novel by Hugh Walpole) Nashville Community Playhouse
    Little Women (The Theatre Guild on the Air: American Broadcasting Company) (starring Katharine Hepburn)
    My Sister Eileen by Joseph Fields and Jerome Chodoroc Nashville Community Playhouse
    Nashville Community Playhouse Membership 1945-46
    Private Lives by Noel Coward Nashville Community Playhouse
    Song of Norwey (a new Operetta on the life and music of Edvard Grieg) (musical adaptation and lyrics) by Robert Wright and George Forrest and (book) by Milton Lazarus (from a play by Homer Curran) Choreography by George Balanchine The Imperial Theatre, NY
    The Skin of Our Teeth by Thornton Wilder Nashville Community Playhouse
    The Time of Your Life by William Saroyan Nashville Community Playhouse
    Uncle Harry by Thomas Job Nashville Community Playhouse
- (1946)
  - (Box 3)
    Angel Street by Patrick Hamilton Nashville Community Playhouse
    Carousel (a new musical play based on Ferenc Molnar’s “Liliom” as adapted by Benjamin F. Glazier) by Richard Rogers and Oscar Hammerstein Majestic Theatre, NY
    Deep Are the Roots by Arnaud d’Usseau and James Gow (staged by Elia Kazan) Fulton Theatre, NY